# **DECLAN RAMSAY**

Email / Skype: declandr@gmail.com
Website: https://declanramsay.co.uk
Github: https://github.com/thelucideffect

Visa: New Zealand / United Kingdom Dual Citizen



## **PROFILE**

I have been working as a Web Developer on commercial projects for 2.5 years. At Alphero I've gotten to work with some of the biggest names in New Zealand, creating beautiful and powerful web apps.

My aim is to create applications that help people and fundamentally improve their web experiences. I am passionate about creating a web that is open, accessible, and diverse.

Coming from a non-Computer Science background I've used the skills from my Composition degree to complement my work as developer, including being able to see wider patterns and implications across a codebase, an appreciation for evaluating different approaches for expressing an idea, and writing code that is consistent and harmonious to the whole.

Outside of work I am serious about my music, having released 3 EPs, a single and an album, and I have toured NZ in 2015 and 2016. I am also beginning to catch the crossfit bug and love a good run.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Developer**

IG Index Limited (September 2017 – Present)

At IG I recently joined the Web Trading Platform Team, bringing my Ember experience to their mature platform. Working in a CI/CD environment with a heavy focus on testing, I was able to expand my experience with testing libraries chai and mocha. In the small team of 5 developers I also spend considerable time pairing with their junior developers, bringing them up to speed with web development and Ember.

#### **Developer**

Alphero Limited (January 2015 – July 2017)

As a Developer at Alphero, I built complex applications as part of the Web team. I primarily worked on two projects, TVNZ's Single Site and The Co-operative Bank. Both were large projects with multiple release cycles. In my role at Alphero I've also been responsible for mentoring interns, peer code reviews, and occasionally leading releases.

**TVNZ Single Site** 

### (September 2016 - July 2017)

Television New Zealand (TVNZ) is New Zealand's largest broadcaster, akin to the BBC in the United Kingdom. Previously, the onDemand and show-information sections of their website had been developed separately, creating a disjointed experience. The project was to unify these streams with a fresh build from the ground-up into a single progressive web app.

On this project I was responsible for significant components within the Single Site project. I was responsible for Authentication, Personalisation, Advertisements, News Feed, and our internal layout generation system. In addition I also provided significant work around analytics, social media integrations, and smaller aspects throughout the project.

I also introduced a style guide and linter for the project with the aim of creating an Alphero Style Guide based on tweaks and feedback from the team throughout the development cycle. This was subsequently rolled throughout the Alphero team.

Languages and technologies used include: HTML5, CSS3/SASS, Javascript (including ES6 features), Ember, GPT, Sentry, Segment, FB and Twitter APIs.

#### The Co-operative Bank (January 2015 - August 2016)

The Co-operative Bank is a Tier 2 Bank in New Zealand, with over 150,000 customers. Alphero joined as their digital partner, revamping their entire digital platform with new mobile and web applications. Both the marketing and online banking "sites" were on a singular platform, meaning users could access low-privileged information such as current balance without logging in and see personalised offers on the marketing site.

Working with a team of 5 client-side developers and The Co-operative Bank's server-side team, I worked on a broad scope of functionality throughout the project, including Payments, Statements, Personalisation, Payees, and a variety of origination flows including Debit MasterCard, Overdrafts, KiwiSaver, Personal Loans, New Accounts, and Join Us.

When the project transitioned between Technical Leads, I released a feature solo and helped bring the new Technical Lead up to speed with the project and codebase. For the feature release I was responsible for estimation, burndown of the tasks via Trello, build and release, and eventually providing feedback via retrospective.

Languages and technologies used include: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and Ember.

#### **Engagement Vice President**

Victoria University of Wellington Students' Association (2014)

I led the VUWSA Engagement Team and I was responsible for ensuring that there is strong communication and opportunities for involvement between VUWSA, its members and students. I led the Engagement team and worked closely with the Clubs and Activities and Campaigns Officer. In particular I had a leading role in our get out the vote campaign "What Are You Voting For?" in the lead up to the 2014 General Election.

#### **Tutor**

Codesmashers (September 2014 – December 2014)

I worked as an early tutor for Codesmashers, teaching the basics of web development with CSS, HTML, and JQuery in an 2-day intensive. I worked with a team of developers to lead small groups of 5-10 people through the course, troubleshooting bugs, and generally assisting where needed.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor of Music**

Victoria University of Wellington 2008 – 2014

### **Victoria Plus Award**

**Dame Malvina Major Foundation Arts Excellence Award** 

# **SKILLS**

#### I Know A Lot About:

- JavaScript (Including ES6)
- HTML5
- CSS3 + SASS

- Ember
- Responsive Web
- Git SCM

## I Know A Bit About / Keen To Learn More About:

- NodeJS
- NoSQL
- TDD

- Extension Development
- Machine Learning
- Angular / React